STEVEN SIMON

Stockton, CA 95204 | C: 415-308-4769 | stevierichard1@gmail.com

SUMMARY

I am a web developer with vast knowledge in both front end and back end languages. My objective is to be the best web developer that I can contribute to the business technology industry. Being in sales management professional with over more than 5 years in business, finance and management roles. Demonstrating passion for building relationships, cultivating partnerships and growing businesses I believe my experience will bring changes and solving various problems to the industry.

SKILLS

- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery,
 Account management Nodejs, API,Bootstrap, Heroku,Git,

 • Contract negotiation expertise Express, MySQL,
- Contract review
- Work force management

EXPERIENCE

10/2012 to 12/2014

Business Development Executive

SCI Tanzania Limited — Dar Es Salaam, Tanzania

- Locates and proposes potential business deals by contacting potential partners; discovering and exploring opportunities.
- Closes new business deals by coordinating requirements; developing and negotiating contracts; integrating contract requirements with business operations
- Carry out market research, competitors and customer surveys
- Working on tender for government and corporate companies
- Plan and carry out direct marketing activities on for major company products and Network services
- Negotiating prices for various products and services from our partners across the globe
- Providing quotations and project proposal to the clients
- Follow up on payments for the closed deals and their execution
- Provision of quarterly report to the top management on deals and pipelines

11/2011 to 10/2012

Sales Executive

Computech ICS Tanzania Limited — Dar Es Salaam, Tanzania

 Plan and carry out direct marketing activities mainly HP products and other brands such as IBM, APC, DELL, CISCO, TRIPPLITE on computers, servers and accessories, Software products including Microsoft projects, Windows Servers, Windows Operating Systems and Network services

- Develop ideas and create offers for direct mail and marketing to major accounts by main market sector
- Monitor and report on activities and provide relevant management information
- Provide sales explanation of products to customers and assist to choose suitable products for their business needs
- Carry out market research, competitor and customer surveys
- Working on tenders for government and corporate companies

08/2007 to 08/2009

Direct Sales Executive

Barclays Bank Tanzania Limited — Arusha, Tanzania

- Acquiring customers through sale of retail products (Loan/Accounts)
 through visit to customers of follow up on leads
- Acquiring new businesses
- Ensuring that customers present all the required documentation as per product specifications
- Certifying all customer documentation and completion of all necessary documentation
- Forwarding customer applications to the sales manager for checking before submission
- Ensure safe custody of customers documentation under their care
- Advise customers of the fates of their applications
- Collecting market/competitor information from the field and feeding this
 to the Lead Generator Leadership with a view to improving Barclays
 products
- Receiving customer complaints and following up with the domicile branch through the sales manager to ensure closure
- Perform other tasks assigned by the sales manager

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Expected in 09/2020 Boot Camp Spot: Information Technology

UC Berkeley Extension — San Francisco, CA

12/2014 BBA: Business Administration And Management

College of Business Education — Dar Es Salaam, Tanzania